Humility should not be equated with low self-esteem.
谦卑不应该与自卑划上等号
[Hardwired to Love]
本能去爱
So, modern psychology, which is descended from humanism
现代心理学是人本主义的延续
is trying to encourage people to believe in themselves.
它努力鼓励人们相信自己
So much so that in the modern world people are aggressive, beyond assertive.
程度至极，现代社会的人们变得强势，自负
So they’ve gone beyond submissiveness, humility,
远离了谦卑、臣服这些美德
being virtuous, admirable, desirable qualities,
没有了那些令人敬佩的优良品性
to the Darwinian world, where only the strong survive.
而转向达尔文倡导的“适者生存”之说
“Survival of the fittest.”
强者生存
We’re being told, “You’ve got to be assertive, aggressive, go for it,
“必须坚定自信，强势果敢。
because you’re number one, you’re worth it.”
你就是第一，去吧你值得拥有。”
All of this kind of thing, which is the antithesis of spiritual culture.
所有这些说法都与灵性文化对立
For the finite, any finite to think that they are the Infinite,
作为一个能力有限的人，如果认为自己是无限的
or, by another name, ‘God’ is the ultimate folly or foolishness—
换句话说认为自己是神，这简直愚蠢透顶
to think that you’re the Supreme Entity,
认为你是至尊个体
that the universe revolves around you.
认为宇宙围着你转。
But what is preventing this is this ego:
这种想法缘于小我，自我
“I’m nobody’s servant, I don’t bow down to anyone.”
“我不是任何人的仆人，我不会向任何人低头。“
And it’s not even true, it’s just posturing.
根本不是这样，真是虚伪
We bow down all the time to all sorts of people
我们一直在向各种人低头
and to all sorts of circumstances.
向各种境遇低声下气
We’re humbled, we’re humilliated. Not just humbled. Humilliated.
不只是恭顺，更甚蒙羞
Prabhupād says in one of his purports in the Bhagavad-gīta,
帕布帕德在《薄伽梵歌原意》中说到
“When one realises that material existence
“当意识到物质生活永远让人困惑费解，
is a constant source of perplexity at every step,
步步为难，
it behooves such a person to approach a spiritual master.”
那么他就有必要去寻找一位灵性导师。”
So we have this ego that won’t allow us to admit,
我们的小我不允许承认自己迷失了，
Guru Mahārāj tells in the beginning of Sri Guru and His Grace,
Guru Maharaj说过，“孰能无过，
“To err is human,
我们犯错是无可避免的，我们是不完美的。”
But, he said, there’s an element within us
但是他说，我们内在有个元素在寻求着完美。”
That’s an interesting situation.
很有意思。
Admittedly we are acknowledging that we’re imperfect,
我们承认自己不完美
and we’re prone to commit mistakes, but there’s something in us
也容易犯错，但我们内在总在寻找着完美，
that’s always searching for perfection, that’s searching for the ideal,
寻找着理想型
the ideal counterpart to our heart;
寻找我们内心渴望的完美
what our heart is searching for
我们心里一直在寻找
despite statistical evidence to the contrary,
尽管数据证实恰恰与之相反，
that you will ever find that
你永远不会找到
in any real and lasting substantial way.
任何真正永久，坚不可摧的存在。
We’re hardwired spiritually to seek
我们天生固有的灵性就在寻找着
beauty, love, charm, sweetness personified.
美、爱、甜蜜的化身
That’s what we’re searching for.
那是我们要找的。
The imperfect is searching for the Perfect.
不完美在寻找着完美，
We’re searching for the ideal, we’re searching for the Absolute.
我们在寻找着完美的理想，绝对存在
That is what life is, that is what existence is, actually.
这实际上，就是生活、生命存在的意义。
It’s not religion, a religious thing, a religious idea.
这并不是什么宗教教条；而是真相。
As once Guru Mahārāj said, “Kṛṣṇa consciousness is Reality,
Guru Maharaj说，奎师那意识是真实的实相。
and it’s in your interest to become acquainted with this Reality.”
认识本真对你有益。”
It’s not Hinduism or an Indian religion,
它不是印度教，或某个教派
or something a particular group of people believe.
或某群人信奉的东西
It’s Reality, and we have to start thinking of It that way.
它是本真，我们必须得重新认知。
Therefore he used that expression: “Reality the Beautiful”.
因此，他才这么表述“美丽的本真，
“Search for Sri Kṛṣṇa, Reality the Beautiful”.
寻找奎师那，那个美丽的本真。”
“The Ultimate Reality is Beautiful.”
终极的本真是美丽的